

Profile

DAVID TAN

- Australian citizen
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-tan-66581a59/
- ♠ 6 Hansen st, Brighton east 3187, Australia
- **** 0416877778
- nttps://github.com/davidtw999
- https://gitlab.com/wtan0019

Prome

Applying my high standard of discipline, fast learning ability, and practical communication skills to contribute and gain experience at the organisation. I have more than 2 years of data analysis experience in deep learning and machine learning models, and more than 5 years of experience in developing IT programming skills, including important skills in front-end and back-end areas (such as C / C) ++ , Python, R, and JavaScript. Recently, Computer Vision and Natural Language Process models are my research area in readiness for upcoming industry applications. I believe my skills, knowledge and data-driven passion will contribute significant values to your firm.

Work experience

Data Scientist

Broadspectrum, Clayton, VIC, Australia

Responsibility

- Develop and maintain actuarial modelling framework, review model design, model controls, model constraints and coding efficiency

- Take responsibility for actuarial modelling projects, utilise existing data for sophisticated statistical analysis and modelling work

Accomplishments

- Built machine learning models of NLP to extract vehicle data from IVMS system
- Automated the process of data validation, reduced the manual works of by 70%

Research Engineer

Monash Action Lab, Caulfield, VIC, Australia

Responsibility

- Develop audio broadcasting and video challenge game applications in real-time by using Python, NodeJs, React, Javascript and HTML5 languages.
- Provide vital technologies such as Web-socket and WebRTC applied to these applications.

Accomplishments

• Successfully implemented audio broadcasting application worked on RaspberryPi and mobile platforms.

Github link for the project: https://github.com/davidtw999/audiobroadcasting

• Successfully implemented video chain online game.

Github link for the project: https://github.com/davidtw999/videoChain

Operation Manager

Umine Pty Ltd, Melbourne, VIC, Australia

Responsibility

- Participated in the team to build the website by using python with Django.
- Provided ongoing IT and technical support, including website and database.

Accomplishments

- Successfully delivered the website to the customers.
- Created the mining software by using Blockchain technology that applied to the cryptocurrency market.

Reporting Analyst

12/2012 - 01/2017

06/2017 - 12/2018

10/2019 - present

05/2019 - present

Malec Brothers Transport , Brighton east, Australia

Responsibilities

- Create daily reports in a spreadsheet format using graphs and charts for analysis
- Interacted with people from various levels of management.

Accomplishments

- Created an algorithm and models by using Excel for data analysis.
- Successfully analysed an extensive price/specification research as part of a solution to offer to clients.

Work experience

IT Support Analyst

Sinex Trading Pty Ltd, Melbourne, VIC, Australia

Responsibilities

- Routine maintenance of hardware and software
- Identify trends and advise peers and IT Operations Manager of recurring incidents **Accomplishments**
- Successfully applied supply chain system for business use.
- Successfully developed the tabular data by using Excel tools.

Intern Software Developer

06/2008 - 06/2009

01/2010 - 12/2012

The Robot cup, Melbourne, VIC, Australia

Responsibility

- Designed a nominal path to play the soccer game.
- Controlled the wheeled robots travelling on a nominated route
- Adjusted accurate robot localisation by using odometry.

Accomplishments

- Successfully implemented a feedback system by using Dead Reckoning technology to adjust the response from the robot's wheels.
- Learned to use Lyapunov function to control the robot's motion.

Education

Data Science

07/2017 - present

Monash University, Caulfield, VIC, Australia

Master's degree GPA: 3.55/4.0 WAM: 82.09/100.0

Mechatronics/Computer Science

01/2004 - 06/2009

The University of Melbourne, Melbourne, VIC, Australia

Bachelor's degree

Data reshaping Web crawler

GPA: 3.21/4.0 (Honours - H2B)

Skills

Back end programming	Operating System
C C++ Python R Bash/Shell	Ubuntu Mac OSX Windows Linux Cloud service
Database	Big Data management
Oracle MySQL MongoDB Firebase	Apache Hadoop Apache Spark MapReduce
Front end programming	Data Visualisation
JavaScript/NodeJS HTML CSS	Tableau D3 JavaScript Power BI R shiny
Data Analysis with ML modelling	Data Analysis with DL modelling
Supervised Learning (Python,R) Unsupervised Learning (Python,R)	NLP (TensorFlow/Keras) CV (TensorFlow/Keras)
Data Wrangling	Interpersonal
Data transformation	Communication Skills

Problem-solving

Teamwork

Awards

FIT5149 Apply Data Analysis

05/2019

Institute of Certified by Monash

https://www.kaggle.com/c/fit5149-2019s1-ass2/leaderboard

Top 1 team for sentiment analysis of Yelp reviews in Kaggle competition by using deep learning models (RNN-LSTM, ULMFIT and BERT)
Github: https://github.com/davidtw999/ulmfitYlep

Datacamp

https://www.datacamp.com/profile/wtan0019

Statement of accomplishment Intermedia Python, Pandas, R and etc.

Hobbies



Exploring

distant lands

Feeling the music



Every kind of sport



Social event

Reading the book

References

Lan du

Broadspectrum

Ph: (03) 9905 4000

Email: lan.du@monash.edu

Peter Chen

Monash Action Lab Ph: (03) 9905 4000

Email: peter.chen@monash.edu

Brandon Tuo

Umine Pty Ltd, 0425893063

Ph: 0425893063

Email: brandon.tuo@infiniteglow.io

Kevin Zhou

Malec Brothers Transport, 0401497633

Ph: 0401497633

Email: kevin.zhou@xh-global.com